ROBERT NG

NERD (Node, Express, React, Database) Stack Developer | Commodity Trader | 🦠 Traveler

New York, NY 10002 • (646) 270-2585 • www.robertkng.com M/RobertNg85@gmail.com

7/ robertkng

Highly motivated self-starter with a wealth of real world experiences. I have found success throughout my career due to my positive attitude, belief that anything can be improved upon, and business acumen. Adapting to new technologies quickly has strengthened my personal and professional knowledge.

PROJECTS

- 1) **Quotinerary:** travellers can submit their travel itinerary and chat with tour operators. Tech: React.js, Node.js, Express.js, PostgreSQL, and Webpack (quotinerary2.herokuapp.com)
- 2) Messages From Mars: web application that passes a random image from NASA's Mars Rover API to Microsoft's Computer Visions API, generating tag words describing that image. Bing's Image Search API takes those words and renders an image.
 - Tech: React.js, Node.js, Express.js, and PostgreSQL (messagesfrommars.herokuapp.com)
- 3) **POI Locator:** search any city where you want to explore their points of interest. Tech: EJS, Node.js, Express.js, MongoDB, and Amadeus API (poilocator2.herokuapp.com)

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

General Assembly New York, NY Web Development Immersive

 Clocked over 1000 hours of development time with a focus on algorithms, data structures, utilizing modern frameworks, libraries and best practices to build full stack web applications.

NG SISU VENTURES, LLC Brooklyn, NY

2015 - 2016

2016

Co-Founder & Managing Member

 Raised over \$300,000 in capital for the acquisition and successful sale of two small businesses with total sales in excess of \$700,000. Managed the day to day operations prior to the sale.

DIRECT ENERGY BUSINESS MARKETING, LLC (Credit Risk), Woodbridge, NJ **Collateral Management Analyst** (Acquisition Hire)

 Worked with management and traders to reduce company's assets held by counterparties in excess of \$40 million due to careful analysis and due diligence of company's trading position reports. This alone saved the company over \$250,000 in interest revenue per month.

HESS CORPORATION (Trade Operations), New York, NY

Middle Office P&L Analyst **Physical and Financial Confirmations Analyst Exchange Margining and Derivatives Analyst**

2012 - 2013

2011 - 2012

2011

• Created trading error reports to reduce the firm's inventory supply trading desk's execution mistakes by over 80%.

- Significantly reduced contracts and confirmations discrepancies by training new employees and working with IT to reduce loading failures between trading systems and online exchange reports.
- Reduced reconciliation process time for exchange P&L report by 2 hours daily through simplifying reports, creating lookup and pivot table templates, and running VBA macros I wrote.

OPUS TRADING FUND (subsidiary of Schonfeld Group), New York, NY Analyst / Trader

 Generated portfolio returns that outperformed the S&P 500 each year by upholding risk management parameters.

2007 - 2010

Javascript, HTML, CSS, React.js, JQuery, AJAX, Node.js, Express.js, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, APIs, MVC, JSON, Webpack, Ruby on Rails, Git, Github, and Heroku.

TECHNOLOGY SKILLS

EDUCATION

Web Development **Immersive General Assembly** New York, NY

User Experience Design Circuit **General Assembly** New York, NY

> BBA in Finance & Investments Zicklin School of Business, Baruch College New York, NY

ADDITIONAL TECH EDUCATION

SEO Training for Startups & Beginners **General Assembly** New York, NY

Python Programming 101 **General Assembly** New York, NY